[
    {
        "title": "Fed Joins OCC, FDIC in Withdrawing Crypto Warnings for U.S. Banks",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2025/04/24/fed-joins-occ-fdic-in-withdrawing-crypto-warnings-for-u-s-banks",
        "published": "Thu, 24 Apr 2025 22:38:40 +0000",
        "summary": "",
        "content": "The Federal Reserve has joined its fellow U.S. banking regulators in deleting its crypto guidance of previous years, including notices that banks should get pre-approvals before they get involved in crypto activity. Now, all three agencies — including the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corp. — have joined in reversing those previous policies, leaving crypto matters at banks in the hands of their managers and compliance executives. In the absence of guidance, the banking industry awaits new laws from Congress to define how the digital assets industry should operate in the U.S. \"These actions ensure the Board's expectations remain aligned with evolving risks and further support innovation in the banking system,\" the Fed said in the Thursday statement announcing the change. Banking supervision of its state member banks is one of the multiple roles performed by the Fed, which is better known for its monetary policy work. The agency's move on Thursday will specifically remove four pieces of crypto guidance the board signed onto in 2022 and 2023, highlighting risks to banks posed by the sector. Fed officials \"will instead monitor banks' crypto-asset activities through the normal supervisory process.\" Read More: FDIC Reverses U.S. Crypto Banking Policy That Demanded Prior Approvals Jesse Hamilton is CoinDesk's deputy managing editor on the Global Policy and Regulation team, based in Washington, D.C. Before joining CoinDesk in 2022, he worked for more than a decade covering Wall Street regulation at Bloomberg News and Businessweek, writing about the early whisperings among federal agencies trying to decide what to do about crypto. He’s won several national honors in his reporting career, including from his time as a war correspondent in Iraq and as a police reporter for newspapers. Jesse is a graduate of Western Washington University, where he studied journalism and history. He has no crypto holdings.  About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "The Federal Reserve",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "U.S.",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "previous years",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "three",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "the Federal Deposit Insurance Corp.",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Congress",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Board",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Fed",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Thursday",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "four",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "2022",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "2023",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "FDIC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Jesse Hamilton",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "the Global Policy and Regulation",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Washington",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "D.C.",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "more than a decade",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Bloomberg News",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Businessweek",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Iraq",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Jesse",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Western Washington University",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.038,
                    "neu": 0.895,
                    "pos": 0.068,
                    "compound": 0.8271
                },
                "label": "positive"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.992432713508606
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9965404272079468
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9998836517333984
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999481439590454
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "neutral",
            "entity_sentiment": {},
            "crypto_scores": {},
            "topics": [
                [
                    "industry",
                    "washington",
                    "federal",
                    "policy",
                    "including",
                    "guidance",
                    "fed",
                    "banking",
                    "banks",
                    "crypto"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "crypto",
                "banks",
                "banking",
                "fed",
                "guidance",
                "including",
                "policy",
                "federal",
                "washington",
                "industry"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-04-25T03:02:23.322674+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "Global Tokenized Real Estate Market Could Explode to $4T by 2035, Deloitte Forecasts",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2025/04/24/global-tokenized-real-estate-market-could-explode-to-usd4t-by-2035-deloitte-forecasts",
        "published": "Thu, 24 Apr 2025 20:16:10 +0000",
        "summary": "",
        "content": "Real estate tokenization—once a niche experiment—may soon become a core pillar of how property is financed, owned and traded, according to a Thursday report by Deloitte Center for Financial Services.The market of tokenized real estate could reach $4 trillion by 2035, growing at a compound annual rate of 27% from the current size of under $300 billion, the firm forecasted. Tokenization of real-world assets (RWA) is a red-hot sector at the intersection of crypto tech and traditional finance. It consists of creating digital versions of assets like bonds, funds and real estate, that represent ownerships on blockchain rails. The process offers operational efficiencies, cheaper and faster settlements and broader investor access. For the real estate sector, tokenization's appeal lies in its ability to automate and simplify complex financial agreements, the report explained, such as launching a real estate fund on-chain with coded rules handling ownership transfers and capital flows. An example for this is Kin Capital's $100 million real estate debt fund tokenization platform Chintai with trust-deed-based lending, Deloitte noted. The report outlines a three-pronged evolution of tokenized property: private real estate funds, securitized loan ownership, and under-construction or undeveloped land projects. Of these, tokenized debt securities are expected to dominate, hitting $2.39 trillion in value by 2035, based on the report's forecast. Private funds could contribute around $1 trillion, while land development assets may account for some $500 billion. Despite the advantages, challenges remain, the report noted, especially around regulation, asset custody, cybersecurity and default scenarios. Read more: Tokenized Funds' Rapid Growth Comes With Red Flags: Moody's Krisztian Sandor is a U.S. markets reporter focusing on stablecoins, tokenization, real-world assets. He graduated from New York University's business and economic reporting program before joining CoinDesk. He holds BTC, SOL and ETH. About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "Thursday",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Deloitte Center for Financial Services",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "$4 trillion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "2035",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "annual",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "27%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "$300 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Kin Capital's",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "$100 million",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Chintai",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Deloitte",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "three",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "$2.39 trillion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "around $1 trillion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "some $500 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Moody's",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Krisztian Sandor",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "U.S.",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "New York University's",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "BTC",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "SOL",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "ETH",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.041,
                    "neu": 0.85,
                    "pos": 0.109,
                    "compound": 0.9435
                },
                "label": "positive"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9909353852272034
                },
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.9999967813491821
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999871253967285
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9990928173065186
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999773502349854
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "neutral",
            "entity_sentiment": {
                "Chintai": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 1
                },
                "BTC": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 1
                },
                "SOL": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 1
                },
                "ETH": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 1
                }
            },
            "crypto_scores": {
                "Chintai": 0.3,
                "BTC": 0.3,
                "SOL": 0.3,
                "ETH": 0.3
            },
            "topics": [
                [
                    "ownership",
                    "sector",
                    "trillion",
                    "assets",
                    "tokenized",
                    "funds",
                    "report",
                    "tokenization",
                    "estate",
                    "real"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "real",
                "estate",
                "tokenization",
                "report",
                "funds",
                "tokenized",
                "assets",
                "trillion",
                "sector",
                "ownership"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-04-25T03:02:23.979357+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "El Salvador's Top Crypto Regulator Meets With U.S. SEC: 'It Was Very Refreshing'",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2025/04/24/el-salvador-s-top-crypto-regulator-meets-with-u-s-sec-it-was-very-refreshing",
        "published": "Thu, 24 Apr 2025 19:29:24 +0000",
        "summary": "",
        "content": "El Salvador’s Comisión Nacional de Activos Digitales (CNAD), the agency in charge of regulating digital assets in the Central American nation, is seeking to establish a cross-border regulatory sandbox with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC). “We want to create international collaboration,” Juan Carlos Reyes, president of the CNAD, told CoinDesk in an interview. “Our biggest message is that digital assets don’t have any geographical barriers. Collaboration with regulators should not have international barriers either.” El Salvador is in a unique situation in that it did not boast of strong financial institutions, or even of an existing ecosystem of developers, when President Nayib Bukele made bitcoin legal tender in 2021. That means the CNAD was able to start with a blank slate when it introduced a regulatory framework tailored to crypto. Almost two years later after Reyes took over the agency, El Salvador’s advanced regulatory framework has incentivized crypto giants such as Tether, Bitfinex and Binance to open shop in the country. The idea, Reyes said, is for the U.S. SEC to now use El Salvador as a live, real-world case study to evaluate streamlined regulatory approaches for digital assets — in other words, for the SEC to learn from El Salvador’s experience as it revamps its own regulatory framework in a post-Gensler world. The pilot program proposed by the CNAD involves different scenarios: a U.S.-licensed traditional finance broker obtaining a digital asset license under CNAD regulations, and the development of two small-scale tokenization offerings facilitated by a CNAD-licensed tokenization company. Each scenario would be capped at $10,000. These initiatives would support some of the objectives laid out by SEC Commissioner Hester Peirce in February, when she wrote that the SEC Crypto Task Force, which she now leads, would take a very different approach towards crypto regulation from here on out. “CNAD really looked at [Pierce’s document] with a critical eye as to how we can help,” Erica Perkin, owner of The Perkin Law Firm and a member of CNAD’s advisory group, told CoinDesk. “We’re here. There's data [the SEC] might want to collect. It's difficult to collect in the U.S. … We've built a framework that's nimble enough to work on the exact issues that the SEC is looking at, and we're here to help and collect information on how we can best do that.” The CNAD met with the SEC’s Crypto Task Force on April 22 to discuss the initiative. The meeting was constructive, according to Reyes and Perkin. “They asked good questions,” Perkin said. “They're in an information-gathering phase. They were engaged and open to discussion.” Reyes has already signed regulatory cooperation agreements with countries such as Argentina and Paraguay. In his view, the SEC seems to be ahead of the curve when it comes to understanding the regulatory needs of digital assets, whereas regulators in other jurisdictions have tended to see crypto regulation from a traditional finance perspective. “The quality of people that make up the SEC Crypto Task Force is quite impressive. They get it. They understand the technology,” Reyes said. “We were able to have discussions that were on point about what’s needed in order to regulate the technology… It was very refreshing.” Tom writes about markets, bitcoin mining and crypto adoption in Latin America. He has a bachelor's degree in English literature from McGill University, and can usually be found in Costa Rica. He holds BTC above CoinDesk's disclosure threshold of $1,000. About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "El Salvador’s",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Comisión Nacional de Activos Digitales (CNAD",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Central American",
                    "NORP"
                ],
                [
                    "the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "SEC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Juan Carlos Reyes",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "El Salvador",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Nayib Bukele",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "2021",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Almost two years later",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Reyes",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Tether",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Bitfinex",
                    "EXCHANGE"
                ],
                [
                    "Binance",
                    "EXCHANGE"
                ],
                [
                    "the U.S. SEC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "post-Gensler",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "two",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "10,000",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Hester Peirce",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "February",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Pierce",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Erica Perkin",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "The Perkin Law Firm",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "CNAD’s",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "U.S.",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Crypto Task Force",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "April 22",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Argentina",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Paraguay",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Tom",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Latin America",
                    "LOC"
                ],
                [
                    "English",
                    "LANGUAGE"
                ],
                [
                    "McGill University",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Costa Rica",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "BTC",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "1,000",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.013,
                    "neu": 0.917,
                    "pos": 0.07,
                    "compound": 0.9778
                },
                "label": "positive"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9877368211746216
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9866646528244019
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999483823776245
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.999996542930603
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9996727705001831
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9575518369674683
                },
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.7521474361419678
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999545812606812
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "neutral",
            "entity_sentiment": {
                "Crypto Task Force": {
                    "sentiment": "positive",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 3
                },
                "BTC": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 1
                }
            },
            "crypto_scores": {
                "Crypto Task Force": 1.3,
                "BTC": 0.3
            },
            "topics": [
                [
                    "framework",
                    "perkin",
                    "el",
                    "digital",
                    "salvador",
                    "reyes",
                    "regulatory",
                    "crypto",
                    "cnad",
                    "sec"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "sec",
                "cnad",
                "crypto",
                "regulatory",
                "reyes",
                "salvador",
                "digital",
                "el",
                "perkin",
                "framework"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-04-25T03:02:24.957624+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "Senator and Ex-Bridgewater CEO McCormick Invests More in Bitcoin as Bill in Works",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2025/04/24/senator-and-ex-bridgewater-ceo-mccormick-invests-more-in-bitcoin-as-bill-in-works",
        "published": "Thu, 24 Apr 2025 19:24:58 +0000",
        "summary": "",
        "content": "U.S. Senator Dave McCormick, the former chief executive of massive hedge fund Bridgewater Associates, is putting his own cash into bitcoin (BTC) as the committee he's on is at the tip of the spear for a legislative effort to regulate the digital assets industry. McCormick has made repeated recent investments in the Bitwise Bitcoin ETF worth hundreds of thousands of dollars, according to disclosures this week. Because of the ranges used in such lawmaker disclosures, the latest amounts invested last month can only be said to be between $310,000 and $700,000. The new investment follows McCormick's disclosure of as much as $450,000 in the Bitwise ETF in February, potentially bringing his total investment closer to a million. His investments represent the bulk of bitcoin investing in Congress this year. Representative Marjorie Taylor Greene, a Georgia Republican, invested a much smaller amount, favoring BlackRock's iShares Bitcoin Trust (IBIT). The Republican senator from Pennsylvania, who has held a series of high-profile government posts throughout his career, is new to the Senate and was put on the Senate Banking's Committee's subcommittee that deals with digital assets. That's the group of lawmakers likely closest to the coming action on crypto legislation that's expected to move this year. As a Senate candidate last year, the former hedge fund exec argued America needed to lead on crypto. He said during the subcommittee's first digital assets hearing in February, \"This Congress must work alongside President Trump to pass bipartisan digital asset legislation that will guide the future of innovation and secure a robust economic future for the U.S.\" While his bitcoin stake is outpacing other lawmakers, he's been putting the bulk of his investments in municipal securities in recent months, the disclosures show. Read More: Congress' Most Prolific Crypto Trader Is a Georgia Trucking Operator Jesse Hamilton is CoinDesk's deputy managing editor on the Global Policy and Regulation team, based in Washington, D.C. Before joining CoinDesk in 2022, he worked for more than a decade covering Wall Street regulation at Bloomberg News and Businessweek, writing about the early whisperings among federal agencies trying to decide what to do about crypto. He’s won several national honors in his reporting career, including from his time as a war correspondent in Iraq and as a police reporter for newspapers. Jesse is a graduate of Western Washington University, where he studied journalism and history. He has no crypto holdings.  About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "U.S.",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Dave McCormick",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Bridgewater Associates",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "BTC",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "McCormick",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "hundreds of thousands",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "this week",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "last month",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "between $310,000 and $700,000",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "as much as $450,000",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Bitwise",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "February",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "a million",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "Congress",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "this year",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Marjorie Taylor Greene",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Georgia",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Republican",
                    "NORP"
                ],
                [
                    "BlackRock",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "iShares Bitcoin Trust",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "IBIT",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Pennsylvania",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Senate",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "the Senate Banking's Committee's",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "last year",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "America",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "first",
                    "ORDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "Trump",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "recent months",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Jesse Hamilton",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "the Global Policy and Regulation",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Washington",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "D.C.",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "2022",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "more than a decade",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Bloomberg News",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Businessweek",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Iraq",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Jesse",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Western Washington University",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.021,
                    "neu": 0.901,
                    "pos": 0.078,
                    "compound": 0.9618
                },
                "label": "positive"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999761581420898
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999977350234985
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9996811151504517
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9949285984039307
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.999929666519165
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999936819076538
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "neutral",
            "entity_sentiment": {
                "BTC": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 0.9997,
                    "mentions": 1
                },
                "IBIT": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 1
                }
            },
            "crypto_scores": {
                "IBIT": 0.3,
                "BTC": 0.2999
            },
            "topics": [
                [
                    "disclosures",
                    "investments",
                    "000",
                    "assets",
                    "senate",
                    "year",
                    "mccormick",
                    "digital",
                    "bitcoin",
                    "crypto"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "crypto",
                "bitcoin",
                "digital",
                "mccormick",
                "year",
                "senate",
                "assets",
                "000",
                "investments",
                "disclosures"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-04-25T03:02:25.814072+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "SoftBank Is Buying Bitcoin Again, After $130M Loss in 2018. Is This Time Different?",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2025/04/24/softbank-is-buying-bitcoin-why-bulls-should-be-worried",
        "published": "Thu, 24 Apr 2025 18:17:41 +0000",
        "summary": "",
        "content": "Japanese investment giant SoftBank is dipping its toes back into crypto by backing a new bitcoin (BTC) investment vehicle, Twenty One Capital, in conjunction with Tether, Bitfinex, and Cantor Fitzgerald. For some, the SoftBank Group—which has $308.7 billion assets under management—taking an interest in bitcoin is a welcome development and another sign of mounting institutional crypto adoption. After all, SoftBank functions more or less like a Japanese sovereign wealth fund, according to Jeff Park, head of alpha strategies at Bitwise. But for seasoned observers, it could be more of a déjà-vu than a breakthrough. Flashback to 2019, SoftBank made headlines when its founder, Masayoshi Son, took a gigantic loss on a personal bitcoin investment. Son had taken exposure to cryptocurrency in late 2017, when the ICO mania was at its peak and bitcoin was trading at an all-time high of around $20,000. With bitcoin now trading at $93,000, Son’s investment would have been very profitable had he held on. But he sold in early 2018 as bitcoin began to crash, resulting in a $130 million loss, according to the Wall Street Journal. So the question investors could be asking themselves now is, would this time be different?  To find a clue, let's take Oracle (ORCL) stock as an example. Recently, U.S. President Donald Trump announced that SoftBank would be part of a $100 billion push to build AI infrastructure in the U.S. in conjunction with OpenAI and Oracle (ORCL).  One would say this is a bullish outcome for ORCL stock. However, since the announcement was made on Jan. 22, coinciding with ORCL topping at $188 per share, the stock fell 28%, while the Nasdaq has gone down 12% in the same period of time. Other outside factors, including macro headwinds and geopolitical tension, could explain the underperformance. It could also be just a plain coincidence. However, one analyst tied this Oracle selloff to Softbank's involvement in the AI infrastructure project. “When SoftBank enters an asset you own, you sell. I don't make the rules,” Quinn Thompson, founder of crypto hedge fund Lekker Capital, wrote in a post on X, citing the Oracle pullback. Helene is a New York-based markets reporter at CoinDesk, covering the latest news from Wall Street, the rise of the spot bitcoin exchange-traded funds and updates on crypto markets. She is a graduate of New York University's business and economic reporting program and has appeared on CBS News, YahooFinance and Nasdaq TradeTalks. She holds BTC and ETH. Tom writes about markets, bitcoin mining and crypto adoption in Latin America. He has a bachelor's degree in English literature from McGill University, and can usually be found in Costa Rica. He holds BTC above CoinDesk's disclosure threshold of $1,000. About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "Oracle",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "ORCL",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Japanese",
                    "NORP"
                ],
                [
                    "SoftBank",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "BTC",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Twenty One",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "Tether",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Bitfinex",
                    "EXCHANGE"
                ],
                [
                    "Cantor Fitzgerald",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "the SoftBank Group",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "$308.7 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Jeff Park",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Bitwise",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "2019",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Masayoshi Son",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "late 2017",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "ICO",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "around $20,000",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "93,000",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Son’s",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "early 2018",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "$130 million",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "the Wall Street Journal",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "U.S.",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Donald Trump",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "$100 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "AI",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "OpenAI",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Jan. 22",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "188",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "28%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "Nasdaq",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "12%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "the same period",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "one",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "Softbank",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Quinn Thompson",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Lekker Capital",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "New York",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "New York University's",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "CBS News",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "YahooFinance",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Nasdaq TradeTalks",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "ETH",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Tom",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Latin America",
                    "LOC"
                ],
                [
                    "English",
                    "LANGUAGE"
                ],
                [
                    "McGill University",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Costa Rica",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "1,000",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.027,
                    "neu": 0.928,
                    "pos": 0.045,
                    "compound": 0.634
                },
                "label": "positive"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.9258675575256348
                },
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.997035026550293
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9857390522956848
                },
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.9894562363624573
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999886751174927
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999806880950928
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "neutral",
            "entity_sentiment": {
                "Oracle": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 0.9963,
                    "mentions": 4
                },
                "ORCL": {
                    "sentiment": "positive",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 4
                },
                "BTC": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 3
                },
                "Donald Trump": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 1
                },
                "ETH": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 1
                }
            },
            "crypto_scores": {
                "ORCL": 1.4,
                "Oracle": 0.5993,
                "BTC": 0.5,
                "Donald Trump": 0.3,
                "ETH": 0.3
            },
            "topics": [
                [
                    "000",
                    "stock",
                    "time",
                    "btc",
                    "orcl",
                    "oracle",
                    "investment",
                    "crypto",
                    "softbank",
                    "bitcoin"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "bitcoin",
                "softbank",
                "crypto",
                "investment",
                "oracle",
                "orcl",
                "btc",
                "time",
                "stock",
                "000"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-04-25T03:02:28.988637+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "Strategy Stock Could Climb as New Rival Twenty One Validates Its Bitcoin Strategy",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2025/04/24/strategy-stock-could-climb-as-new-rival-twenty-one-validates-its-bitcoin-strategy",
        "published": "Thu, 24 Apr 2025 16:57:41 +0000",
        "summary": "",
        "content": "Michael Saylor's bitcoin buying strategy had both believers and skeptics. But a new rival just emerged, already holding nearly $4 billion BTC on its balance sheet—and it's a bullish sign, according to at least one Wall Street analyst.   When SoftBank, Tether, and Cantor Fitzgerald unveiled plans to launch a new bitcoin investment company called Twenty One, structured explicitly around holding bitcoin as its primary business, many called it a significant rival to Saylor's Strategy (MSTR). Its day-one bitcoin balance sheet holding would rank it as the third-largest publicly held bitcoin treasury on day one. In traditional finance, one could argue that such a big competition could hamper a dominant company's market share and capital raise opportunities, especially since Twenty One is already potentially launching with over 42,000 BTC at launch (worth nearly $4 billion at spot price).  However, TD Cowen analysts Lance Vitanza and Jonnathan Navarrete see it as the exact opposite: \"The proposed launch of Twenty One reflects the most-meaningful validation of Strategy's bitcoin treasury operations to date,\" leaving the analysts \"incrementally bullish\" on the stock.  The analysts added that the new rival could even convert MSTR's biggest skeptics, institutional investors, into believers in Saylor's bitcoin buying strategy. The move would also increase demand for bitcoin from a high-profile entrant, which could outweigh any pressure on Strategy’s cost of capital and attract more capital into buying bitcoin.  “Certainly this is what Michael Saylor professes to believe,” the analysts wrote, pointing to the Strategy founder’s long-standing push for more companies to adopt similar strategies. TD Cowen maintained its $550 price target for MSTR and projects the company could hold 757,000 BTC by the end of fiscal year 2027 — about 3.6% of bitcoin’s total supply. The analysts said that if bitcoin hits an average price of $170,000 by then, TD Cowen estimates that stash could be worth $129 billion. The bullish impact of this rivalry is already prominent in the market. The shares of Cantor Equity Partners (CEP), Twenty One's SPAC vehicle, have already climbed as much as 130% since the announcement, while MSTR stocks held strong.  Read more: Cantor Skyrockets 130% as Traders FOMO Into the Stock on Bitcoin SPAC Frenzy Disclaimer: Parts of this article were generated with the assistance from AI tools and reviewed by our editorial team to ensure accuracy and adherence to our standards. For more information, see CoinDesk’s full AI Policy. Helene is a New York-based markets reporter at CoinDesk, covering the latest news from Wall Street, the rise of the spot bitcoin exchange-traded funds and updates on crypto markets. She is a graduate of New York University's business and economic reporting program and has appeared on CBS News, YahooFinance and Nasdaq TradeTalks. She holds BTC and ETH. About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "Michael Saylor's",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "nearly $4 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "at least one",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "SoftBank",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Tether",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Cantor Fitzgerald",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Twenty One",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "Saylor's Strategy (MSTR",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "third",
                    "ORDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "day one",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "over 42,000",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "TD Cowen",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Lance Vitanza",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Jonnathan Navarrete",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "MSTR",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Saylor",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Michael Saylor",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "550",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "757,000",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "BTC",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "the end of fiscal year 2027",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "about 3.6%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "170,000",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "$129 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Cantor Equity Partners",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Twenty One's",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "SPAC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "as much as 130%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "130%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "AI",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "New York",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "New York University's",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "CBS News",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "YahooFinance",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Nasdaq TradeTalks",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "ETH",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.028,
                    "neu": 0.894,
                    "pos": 0.078,
                    "compound": 0.975
                },
                "label": "positive"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.9997584223747253
                },
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.9984011054039001
                },
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.9999997615814209
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.999632716178894
                },
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.9936010241508484
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999784231185913
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "positive",
            "entity_sentiment": {
                "MSTR": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 0.9332,
                    "mentions": 4
                },
                "BTC": {
                    "sentiment": "positive",
                    "confidence": 0.9999,
                    "mentions": 4
                },
                "ETH": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 1
                }
            },
            "crypto_scores": {
                "BTC": 1.3999,
                "MSTR": 0.5866,
                "ETH": 0.3
            },
            "topics": [
                [
                    "launch",
                    "price",
                    "rival",
                    "btc",
                    "saylor",
                    "mstr",
                    "analysts",
                    "new",
                    "strategy",
                    "bitcoin"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "bitcoin",
                "strategy",
                "new",
                "analysts",
                "mstr",
                "saylor",
                "btc",
                "rival",
                "price",
                "launch"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-04-25T03:02:31.596490+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "Coinbase Introduces Free Conversion for PayPal's PYUSD as Stablecoin Competition Intensifies",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/business/2025/04/24/coinbase-introduces-free-conversion-for-paypals-pyusd-as-stablecoin-competition-intensifies",
        "published": "Thu, 24 Apr 2025 16:02:37 +0000",
        "summary": "",
        "content": "Crypto exchange Coinbase (COIN) said it will introduce free conversions between PayPal’s dollar-pegged stablecoin, PYUSD, and the U.S. currency in a move aimed at accelerating the shift toward on-chain payments. The move, open to both retail and institutional customers, is part of a partnership aimed at promoting PYUSD as a payment currency. Coinbase also plans to use its platform to offer PYUSD to PayPal’s extensive network of merchant partners, which could ease the use of stablecoins in everyday transactions. Stablecoins — digital tokens pegged to traditional currencies, predominantly the dollar — are one of the fastest-growing sectors in crypto. They are marketed as a faster and cheaper alternative to legacy payment systems, and are increasingly popular for payments across borders. Standard Chartered projected the sector to grow to $2 trillion by 2028 from the current $220 billion. With regulation for stablecoins advancing in the U.S., the competition is heating up among issuers while banks and traditional payment firms are also eyeing the market. Binance, the largest crypto exchange, and Circle, issuer of the second largest dollar-backed stablecoin, have already linked up to use Circle's USDC as a trading pair and payment method. Circle introduced a remittances network this week. Market leader Tether, issuer of the $140 billion USDT, is mulling issuing a stablecoin designed for U.S. users. Meanwhile, PayPal, whose stablecoin debuted in 2023 and has grown to $860 million, recently introduced a 3.7% annual yield on PYUSD for U.S. token holders to attract more users. Krisztian Sandor is a U.S. markets reporter focusing on stablecoins, tokenization, real-world assets. He graduated from New York University's business and economic reporting program before joining CoinDesk. He holds BTC, SOL and ETH. About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "COIN",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "PayPal",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "PYUSD",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "U.S.",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Coinbase",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "everyday",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Standard Chartered",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "$2 trillion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "2028",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "$220 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Binance",
                    "EXCHANGE"
                ],
                [
                    "Circle",
                    "LOC"
                ],
                [
                    "second",
                    "ORDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "USDC",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "this week",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Tether",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "$140 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "2023",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "$860 million",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "3.7%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "annual",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Krisztian Sandor",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "New York University's",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "BTC",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "SOL",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "ETH",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.0,
                    "neu": 0.945,
                    "pos": 0.055,
                    "compound": 0.9231
                },
                "label": "positive"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9943605065345764
                },
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.9998636245727539
                },
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.9761660695075989
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999932050704956
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "neutral",
            "entity_sentiment": {
                "COIN": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 0.9992,
                    "mentions": 1
                },
                "PYUSD": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 0.9971,
                    "mentions": 4
                },
                "USDC": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 1
                },
                "BTC": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 1
                },
                "SOL": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 1
                },
                "ETH": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 1
                }
            },
            "crypto_scores": {
                "PYUSD": 0.5994,
                "USDC": 0.3,
                "BTC": 0.3,
                "SOL": 0.3,
                "ETH": 0.3,
                "COIN": 0.2998
            },
            "topics": [
                [
                    "coinbase",
                    "dollar",
                    "use",
                    "paypal",
                    "crypto",
                    "circle",
                    "pyusd",
                    "stablecoin",
                    "stablecoins",
                    "payment"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "payment",
                "stablecoins",
                "stablecoin",
                "pyusd",
                "circle",
                "crypto",
                "paypal",
                "use",
                "dollar",
                "coinbase"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-04-25T03:02:32.698466+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "Shaq Inks Deal to Settle With FTX Investors Over Boosting Failed Crypto Exchange",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2025/04/24/shaq-inks-deal-to-settle-with-ftx-investors-over-boosting-failed-crypto-exchange",
        "published": "Thu, 24 Apr 2025 15:33:49 +0000",
        "summary": "",
        "content": "Shaquille O’Neal has reached a settlement agreement with a group of FTX investors who accused him of enabling the failed crypto exchange’s fraud by acting as a celebrity promoter, according to a court filing. Details of the settlement agreement, including the amount O’Neal will pay, have not yet been disclosed. Plaintiffs in the case are seeking up to $21 billion in total damages from O’Neal and other promoters, former executives and other insiders. The former basketball star-turned-business mogul was just one of a host of celebrity promoters named in the class action suit. Other athletes, including tennis player Naomi Osaka, baseball player Shohei Otani, basketball player Steph Curry and retired football player Tom Brady were also named as defendants, along with comedian Larry David, Shark Tank star Kevin O’Leary, and model Gisele Bundchen. Though O’Neal is the first big-name defendant in the case to settle on Wednesday, seven other celebrity promoters and former executives reached a settlement agreement with the investors back in 2023, including Jaguars quarterback Trevor Lawrence, and Youtubers Tom Nash, Graham Stephan and Andrei Jikh. The first tranche of settlements were relatively small, totalling a collective $1.4 million. O’Neal’s settlement with FTX investors is not his first tied to a promotion of a failed crypto project. Last year, O’Neal and several of his associates agreed to pay $11 million to Astral non-fungible token (NFT) holders who lost money in the Solana-based project he founded and promoted. On the news team at CoinDesk, Cheyenne focuses on crypto regulation and crime. Cheyenne is originally from Houston, Texas. She studied political science at Tulane University in Louisiana. In December 2021, she graduated from CUNY's Craig Newmark Graduate School of Journalism, where she focused on business and economics reporting. She has no significant crypto holdings.  About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "Shaquille",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "FTX",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "up to $21 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Naomi Osaka",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Shohei Otani",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Steph Curry",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Tom Brady",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Larry David",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Shark Tank",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Kevin O’Leary",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Gisele Bundchen",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "first",
                    "ORDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "Wednesday",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "seven",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "2023",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Jaguars",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Trevor Lawrence",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Youtubers Tom Nash",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Graham Stephan",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Andrei Jikh",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "$1.4 million",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Last year",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "$11 million",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Astral",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "NFT",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Solana",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Cheyenne",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Houston",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Texas",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Tulane University",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Louisiana",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "December 2021",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "CUNY",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Craig Newmark Graduate School of Journalism",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.083,
                    "neu": 0.841,
                    "pos": 0.077,
                    "compound": -0.4588
                },
                "label": "negative"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.7434518337249756
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.6017296314239502
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.997424840927124
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999852180480957
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "neutral",
            "entity_sentiment": {
                "FTX": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 0.682,
                    "mentions": 2
                },
                "Solana": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 0.9879,
                    "mentions": 1
                },
                "Cheyenne": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 2
                }
            },
            "crypto_scores": {
                "Cheyenne": 0.4,
                "FTX": 0.3364,
                "Solana": 0.2976
            },
            "topics": [
                [
                    "pay",
                    "investors",
                    "promoters",
                    "including",
                    "agreement",
                    "celebrity",
                    "crypto",
                    "player",
                    "settlement",
                    "neal"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "neal",
                "settlement",
                "player",
                "crypto",
                "celebrity",
                "including",
                "investors",
                "promoters",
                "agreement",
                "pay"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-04-25T03:02:37.009391+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "Stablecoin Legislation Must Ensure Financial Privacy",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/opinion/2025/04/24/stablecoin-legislation-must-ensure-financial-privacy",
        "published": "Thu, 24 Apr 2025 15:32:06 +0000",
        "summary": "",
        "content": "Both the U.S. Senate and House are considering bills creating a regulatory framework for stablecoins, and all of the usual crypto-skeptic refrains have been sung, including the hymn that crypto is for crime. For instance, Senator Elizabeth Warren (D-MA) warned that the Senate’s GENIUS Act “will supercharge the financing of terrorism.” During debate on the House’s STABLE Act, Representative Brad Sherman (D-CA) worried about the use of “unhosted wallets to evade” anti-money laundering provisions. Not surprisingly, both the GENIUS and STABLE Acts include significant sections on illicit finance, including subjecting stablecoin issuers to the Bank Secrecy Act (BSA). But lawmakers must ensure that the bills’ anti-money laundering measures don’t open the door to unfettered financial surveillance of stablecoin users. Stablecoins are crypto tokens that are pegged to the value of another asset, like the U.S. dollar. The general idea is that the stable value of these tokens will promote their use as a digital medium of exchange. Stablecoins can be thought of both as an improvement to existing payment rails and as a way to bring the U.S. dollar “on-chain.” In other words, stablecoins are a 21st-century upgrade to cash. The Senate and the House have both advanced bills that would create a regulatory regime for “permitted stablecoin issuers” aimed, in part, at ensuring that stablecoins are, in fact, stable. But these days, conversations about the dollar, financial services, and crypto seem to go hand-in-hand with conversations about preventing illicit finance. The BSA requires financial institutions to help federal agencies detect and prevent money laundering and other crimes by, among other things, keeping records of transactions and filing reports with the government. Both the GENIUS Act and the STABLE Act tackle illicit finance concerns by stating clearly that a permitted stablecoin issuer “shall be treated as a financial institution for the purposes of the Bank Secrecy Act.” Designating a permitted stablecoin issuer as a financial institution is comparatively non-controversial. Putting aside the question of whether the BSA is a good (or constitutional) way to manage illicit finance risks, permitted stablecoin issuers look a lot like other entities, like banks and trust companies, that are already BSA financial institutions. But it’s not quite so simple. The BSA’s surveillance framework requires financial institutions to “know their customers” and to monitor transactions taking place through the institution. However, such surveillance does not extend to transactions that take place between individuals without the involvement of an institution. For example, the BSA doesn’t apply when cash changes hands between two people, allowing individuals to transact privately. While it’s infeasible to track cash transactions in the manner prescribed by the BSA, stablecoins can be tracked across a blockchain as they move between holders, even when the transfers happen between wallets that are unhosted by intermediaries. This characteristic is tempting to those who may want to extend BSA surveillance beyond its already expansive (and constitutionally infirm) boundaries. Fundamentally, digital asset transactions that are genuinely peer-to-peer should not be subject to greater government surveillance than peer-to-peer transactions in cash. Applying anti-money laundering provisions to unhosted wallets — which more closely resemble physical wallets holding cash than bank accounts — would be a massive expansion of financial surveillance and an unwelcome intrusion into the abilities of Americans to order their financial lives outside the eyes of the government. Both the GENIUS and STABLE Acts make clear — to varying degrees — that stablecoin issuers must have customer identification programs only for customers who either hold accounts “with the permitted payment stablecoin issuer” (GENIUS) or who are “initial holders” of a payment stablecoin (STABLE). But the other BSA requirements the bills would impose on stablecoin issuers, including maintaining anti-money laundering compliance programs, retention of records of stablecoin transactions, monitoring and reporting suspicious activity, are not so clearly limited. This leaves the door open to the imposition of broader surveillance requirements on stablecoin transactions that take place away from the issuer, which would be a major encroachment on Americans’ rights to transact privately. Fortunately, the sponsors of both bills seem to read the surveillance obligations narrowly. Representative Bryan Steil (R-WI), one of the sponsors of the STABLE Act, explained during the bill’s markup that requiring BSA surveillance of “every single self-hosted wallet” would “be a dramatic invasion of personal liberty” and that “Americans should not be treated the same as financial institutions.” And Senator Bill Hagerty (R-TN), one of the sponsors of the GENIUS Act, said during that bill’s markup that “[r]equiring issuers to monitor transactions on various blockchains would be costly and . . . time-consuming.” This sentiment about the scope of the BSA obligations imposed must be clearly reflected in the text of both bills to definitively close the door to more expansive future interpretations. Despite the characterizations by some skeptical members of Congress, preserving financial privacy is not simply a gift to criminals. Easy government access to financial information poses risks to everyone, particularly those with unpopular political views or anyone otherwise in the minority. Such surveillance is at odds with the rights of free people (including rights recognized in the U.S. Constitution) to live without unwarranted governmental monitoring. One step to ensuring that those rights are not further infringed is to guarantee that the stablecoin legislation under consideration unequivocally protects from surveillance stablecoin transactions occurring without a financial intermediary. Note: The views expressed in this column are those of the author and do not necessarily reflect those of CoinDesk, Inc. or its owners and affiliates. Jennifer J. Schulp is the director of financial regulation studies at the CMFA. About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "the U.S. Senate",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "House",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Elizabeth Warren",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Senate",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Brad Sherman",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "the Bank Secrecy Act",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "BSA",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "U.S.",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "21st-century",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "these days",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "the GENIUS Act",
                    "LAW"
                ],
                [
                    "two",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "Americans",
                    "NORP"
                ],
                [
                    "STABLE",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Bryan Steil",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "one",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "the STABLE Act",
                    "LAW"
                ],
                [
                    "Bill Hagerty",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Congress",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "the U.S. Constitution",
                    "EVENT"
                ],
                [
                    "One",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk, Inc.",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Jennifer J. Schulp",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "CMFA",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.041,
                    "neu": 0.841,
                    "pos": 0.118,
                    "compound": 0.9976
                },
                "label": "positive"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.9472318887710571
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9998308420181274
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9983524084091187
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.990605890750885
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9976239800453186
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.999992847442627
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999303817749023
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9968401193618774
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.8993896245956421
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9992684721946716
                },
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.7233837246894836
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9758543372154236
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9992055296897888
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "neutral",
            "entity_sentiment": {
                "One": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 0.9411,
                    "mentions": 1
                }
            },
            "crypto_scores": {
                "One": 0.2882
            },
            "topics": [
                [
                    "genius",
                    "bills",
                    "stablecoins",
                    "act",
                    "stable",
                    "transactions",
                    "surveillance",
                    "bsa",
                    "financial",
                    "stablecoin"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "stablecoin",
                "financial",
                "bsa",
                "surveillance",
                "transactions",
                "stable",
                "act",
                "stablecoins",
                "bills",
                "genius"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-04-25T03:02:40.070285+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "Crypto for Advisors: Crypto — No Longer the Wild West?",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/coindesk-indices/2025/04/23/crypto-for-advisors-crypto-no-longer-the-wild-west",
        "published": "Thu, 24 Apr 2025 15:00:00 +0000",
        "summary": "",
        "content": "In today’s crypto for advisors, Dovile Silenskyte from WisdomTree talks about the growth of crypto products and how they’ve evolved into a strategic investment allocation. Then, Kim Klemballa from CoinDesk Indices answers questions about digital asset benchmarks and trends in Ask an Expert. – Sarah Morton You’re reading Crypto for Advisors, CoinDesk’s weekly newsletter that unpacks digital assets for financial advisors. Subscribe here to get it every Thursday. Crypto is no longer the “Wild West” of investing. Once dismissed as mere speculative bets, digital assets have matured into a credible and increasingly strategic component of institutional portfolios. Figure 1: Global assets under management (AUM) in physical crypto ETPs Source: Bloomberg, WisdomTree. 01 April 2025. Historical performance is not an indication of future performance and any investment may go down in value. As of the end of Q1 2025, global assets under management (AUM) in physical bitcoin exchange-traded products (ETPs) was more than $100 billion. That figure signals deep, sustained conviction from institutional investors, meaning this is no longer just the realm of early adopters. Today, sovereign wealth funds, pension schemes and asset managers are allocating to crypto at scale. After more than 15 years of development, multiple boom-and-bust cycles and a global user base exceeding half a billion people, crypto has proven it is no passing trend. Bitcoin has emerged as a crypto macro asset — scarce, decentralized and increasingly positioned as a core holding within diversified multi-asset portfolios. But here’s the catch — crypto allocations are still under-diversified. Despite growing adoption, most crypto portfolios remain narrowly concentrated in bitcoin. That is a legacy mindset and one that is fundamentally flawed. Investors wouldn’t allocate their entire equity exposure to Apple, nor rely on a single bond to represent fixed income. Yet that is precisely how many still treat crypto. Diversification is foundational in traditional finance. It spreads risk, enhances resilience and unlocks access to broader opportunity sets. The same principle holds in digital assets. The cryptocurrency universe has expanded far beyond bitcoin, evolving into a dynamic ecosystem of distinct technologies, use cases and investment theses. Smart contract platforms like Ethereum, Solana and Cardano are building decentralized infrastructure for everything from decentralized finance (DeFi) to non-fungible tokens (NFTs), each with unique trade-offs in scalability, security and network design. Meanwhile, Polkadot is advancing interoperability, enabling seamless communication across chains — a key building block for a multi-chain future. Beyond these Layer 1 blockchains, we are seeing rapid innovation in: Each of these sectors carries its own risk-return profile, adoption curve and regulatory trajectory. Treating them as interchangeable, or worse, ignoring them altogether, is similar to reducing global equity investing to a single tech stock. It is not just outdated — it is strategically inefficient. Diversification in crypto is not about avoiding risk, but rather, capturing the full spectrum of innovation. In a multi-chain, multi-thesis world, failing to diversify means leaving opportunity on the table. The case for crypto indices The reality is that most investors do not have the time, tools or technical expertise to keep up with 24/7 crypto markets. Crypto indices offer a powerful solution for those seeking broad, systematic exposure without having to dive into tokenomics, validator uptime or network upgrades. Just as equity investors rely on benchmarks such as the S&P 500 or MSCI indices, diversified crypto indices allow investors to access the market passively — with scale, structure and simplicity. No guesswork, no token-picking, no need for constant rebalances. Just clean, rules-based exposure to the evolving crypto landscape. - Dovile Silenskyte, Director of Digital Assets Research, WisdomTree Q. Why is diversification important in crypto? A. Among over 20,000 listed cryptocurrencies, bitcoin now accounts for approximately 65% of total market capitalization. Diversification is key for institutional investors to manage volatility and capture broader opportunities. Indices can be an efficient way of tracking asset class performance, while products like exchange-traded funds (ETFs) and separately managed accounts (SMAs) can provide exposure to multiple cryptocurrencies at once, potentially helping to spread risk.  Q. What trends are you seeing in digital assets? A. Institutional investors are entering the market, pushing digital assets from a niche investment into a key asset class. EY-Parthenon and Coinbase conducted a survey of more than 350 institutional investors around the world in January 2025. Of the investors surveyed, 87% plan to increase overall allocations to crypto in 2025, spanning a variety of options such as exchange-traded products (ETPs), investments in digital asset companies, stablecoins, futures and thematic mutual funds. Per the survey, 55% hold spot crypto through ETPs, with 69% of those who plan to own spot crypto planning to do so using registered vehicles. Q. Does a broad-based benchmark exist in crypto? A. There are broad benchmarks in digital assets. At CoinDesk Indices, we launched the CoinDesk 20 Index in January 2024, to capture the performance of top digital assets and act as a gateway to measure, trade and invest in the ever-expanding crypto asset class. Designed with liquidity and diversification in mind, the CoinDesk 20 has generated an unprecedented $14.5 billion in total trading volume and is available in twenty investment vehicles globally. CoinDesk Indices also has the CoinDesk 80 Index, CoinDesk 100 Index (CoinDesk 20 + CoinDesk 80) and CoinDesk Memecoin Index, amongst others. - Kim Klemballa, Head of Marketing, CoinDesk Indices Dovile Silenskyte is a director of digital assets research at WisdomTree. Prior to joining WisdomTree in May 2024, Dovile worked as an index equity product strategist at BlackRock. In her current role she is responsible for conducting analysis for in-house digital assets publications and assisting the sales team with client queries around products and markets. Dovile holds a MSc in Finance from Texas A&M University – Commerce. She is also a chartered financial analyst (CFA). Kim Greenberg Klemballa is the head of marketing for CoinDesk Indices. Kim brings approximately 20 years of experience in the financial industry and is currently responsible for leading the marketing and branding initiatives. Previously, Kim was head of marketing for VettaFi, led strategic beta and ETF marketing at Columbia Threadneedle, served as director of marketing at Aberdeen Standard Investments (formerly ETF Securities) and was vice president of marketing at Source Exchange Traded Investments (now Invesco). She also held multiple positions at Guggenheim Investments. Kim also holds the Certified Meeting Planner (CMP) and Certified Tradeshow Marketer (CTSM) designations.  About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "today",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Dovile Silenskyte",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "WisdomTree",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "Kim Klemballa",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk Indices",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Sarah Morton",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Crypto for Advisors",
                    "WORK_OF_ART"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "weekly",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Thursday",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Crypto",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "AUM",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Bloomberg",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "April 2025",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "the end of",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "more than $100 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Today",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "more than 15 years",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "half a billion",
                    "QUANTITY"
                ],
                [
                    "Bitcoin",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Apple",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Smart",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Ethereum",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Solana",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Cardano",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "DeFi",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Polkadot",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Layer 1",
                    "LAW"
                ],
                [
                    "24/7",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "MSCI indices",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Digital Assets Research",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "WisdomTree Q.",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "20,000",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "approximately 65%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "EY-Parthenon",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Coinbase",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "more than 350",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "January 2025",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "87%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "2025",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "55%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "69%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk 20 Index",
                    "LAW"
                ],
                [
                    "January 2024",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "the CoinDesk 20",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "$14.5 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "twenty",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "the CoinDesk 80 Index",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk 100 Index (CoinDesk 20 + CoinDesk 80",
                    "LAW"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk Memecoin Index",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "May 2024",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Dovile",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "BlackRock",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Finance",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Texas A&M University – Commerce",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "CFA",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Kim Greenberg Klemballa",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Kim",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "approximately 20 years",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "VettaFi",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "ETF",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Columbia Threadneedle",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Aberdeen Standard Investments",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Source Exchange Traded Investments",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Invesco",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Guggenheim Investments",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "the Certified Meeting Planner",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "CMP",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Certified Tradeshow Marketer",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "CTSM",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.037,
                    "neu": 0.855,
                    "pos": 0.109,
                    "compound": 0.9969
                },
                "label": "positive"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9997617602348328
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.998873770236969
                },
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.7864792943000793
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.5999692678451538
                },
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.9990642666816711
                },
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.9999927282333374
                },
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.9614129662513733
                },
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.8668940663337708
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9768030643463135
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999682903289795
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999992847442627
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999992847442627
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999767541885376
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999880790710449
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999862909317017
                }
            ],
