[
    {
        "title": "Terraform Labs to Open Claims Portal for Investors on March 31",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2025/03/29/terraform-labs-to-open-claims-portal-for-investors-on-march-31",
        "published": "Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:14:01 +0000",
        "summary": "Going over files with laptops (Scott Graham/Unsplash)",
        "content": "Terraform Labs, the firm behind the collapsed Luna token and the TerraUSD stablecoin, will open a portal on March 31 to allow investors to file claims for crypto losses tied to the company’s downfall and subsequent bankruptcy. The online system, operated by claims administrator Kroll, is part of the company's court-supervised wind-down process. Investors have until April 30 at 11:59 p.m. ET to submit claims through claims.terra.money. Late submissions will not be considered, meaning those who miss the deadline forfeit their right to any recovery, according to a Medium post. Eligible claims must be tied to specific cryptocurrencies listed in the case documents and held during the period surrounding the Terra ecosystem's collapse. Notably, assets with less than $100 in on-chain liquidity and certain others—like Terra 2.0's Luna—will not qualify. Claimants must also submit proof of ownership. The preferred method is read-only API keys from exchanges, which the administrator considers more reliable than screenshots or manually uploaded documents. The post adds that those using manual evidence may face extended review periods or risk their claims being denied altogether. Once filed, claims will be reviewed and verified. Initial decisions will be shared within 90 days after the deadline and approved claims will be eligible for pro rata distributions once processing concludes. The Terra ecosystem collapsed in 2022, leading to the largest destruction of wealth in just three days in the cryptocurrency space’s history. LUNA’s market capitalization plunged from over $41 billion to $6 million in that period.Read more: Terraform Labs, Do Kwon Agree to Pay SEC a Combined $4.5B in Civil Fraud Case Francisco is a reporter for CoinDesk with a passion for cryptocurrencies and personal finance. Before joining CoinDesk he worked at major financial and crypto publications. He owns bitcoin, ether, solana, and PAXG above CoinDesk's $1,000 disclosure threshold. About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "Terraform Labs",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Luna",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "TerraUSD",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "March 31",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Kroll",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "April 30",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "11:59 p.m.",
                    "TIME"
                ],
                [
                    "Terra",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "less than $100",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Terra 2.0's",
                    "LAW"
                ],
                [
                    "API",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "90 days",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "2022",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "just three days",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "LUNA",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "over $41 billion to $6 million",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "SEC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Combined",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "4.5B",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "solana",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "1,000",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.079,
                    "neu": 0.86,
                    "pos": 0.061,
                    "compound": -0.7184
                },
                "label": "negative"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9998537302017212
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9998575448989868
                },
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.9335773587226868
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999312162399292
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "neutral",
            "entity_sentiment": {
                "Luna": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 0.8679,
                    "mentions": 2
                },
                "Terra": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 0.9281,
                    "mentions": 5
                }
            },
            "crypto_scores": {
                "Terra": 0.6856,
                "Luna": 0.3736
            },
            "topics": [
                [
                    "case",
                    "collapsed",
                    "submit",
                    "terraform",
                    "tied",
                    "read",
                    "coindesk",
                    "luna",
                    "terra",
                    "claims"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "claims",
                "terra",
                "luna"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-03-29T21:07:56.131766+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "Bitcoin Miner MARA Starts Massive $2B Stock Sale Plan to Buy More BTC",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2025/03/29/bitcoin-miner-mara-starts-massive-usd2b-at-the-market-stock-sale-plan-to-buy-more-btc",
        "published": "Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:02:04 +0000",
        "summary": "Marathon Digital CEO Fred Thiel (CoinDesk \"First Mover\" screenshot)",
        "content": "Bitcoin mining company MARA Holdings (MARA) is launching a fresh $2 billion stock offering to buy more bitcoin, continuing its plan of buying BTC in the open market through capital raise while sticking to its \"Hodl\" strategy.  According to a Form 8-K  and a new prospectus filed with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), MARA entered into an at-the-market (ATM) equity program with a group of investment banks including Barclays, BMO Capital Markets, BTIG, Cantor Fitzgerald, and others. The proceeds of the offering, which will see brokers selling shares of the miner from time to time, will be used mainly for the acquisition of bitcoin in the open market.  \"We currently intend to use the net proceeds from this offering for general corporate purposes, including the acquisition of bitcoin and for working capital,\" MARA said in its prospectus.  This new fresh stock sales plan follows a previous ATM offering that targeted up to $1.5 billion for the miner.   MARA has adopted Michael Saylor's strategy of raising funds through equity and convertible bond offerings and buying bitcoin in the open market. The miner now holds 46,376 BTC in its treasury, making it the second-largest bitcoin stash among publicly traded companies, behind Strategy’s 506,137 BTC. The plan to buy bitcoin in the open market was adopted by the miner last year, even though a miner can theoretically mine bitcoin at a discount to the spot price. The industry became challenging after last year's halving cut mining rewards by half, squeezing profit margins on the back of rising costs. This made buying bitcoin in the open market, alongside mining, a relatively better strategy for the miners. Read more: Bitcoin Mining Is So Rough a Miner Adopted Michael Saylor's Successful BTC Strategy Francisco is a reporter for CoinDesk with a passion for cryptocurrencies and personal finance. Before joining CoinDesk he worked at major financial and crypto publications. He owns bitcoin, ether, solana, and PAXG above CoinDesk's $1,000 disclosure threshold. About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "MARA Holdings",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "$2 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "BTC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "SEC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "ATM",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Barclays",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "BMO Capital Markets",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Cantor Fitzgerald",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "up to $1.5 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Michael Saylor's",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "46,376",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "second",
                    "ORDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "506,137",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "last year",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "last year's",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "half",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "solana",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "1,000",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.006,
                    "neu": 0.91,
                    "pos": 0.084,
                    "compound": 0.9719
                },
                "label": "positive"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999279975891113
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9997358918190002
                },
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.9999405145645142
                },
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.9962306618690491
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999837875366211
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "neutral",
            "entity_sentiment": {},
            "crypto_scores": {},
            "topics": [
                [
                    "coindesk",
                    "btc",
                    "mining",
                    "offering",
                    "open",
                    "mara",
                    "strategy",
                    "miner",
                    "market",
                    "bitcoin"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "bitcoin",
                "market",
                "miner"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-03-29T21:07:56.846473+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "FTX to Begin $11.4B Creditor Payouts in May After Years-Long Bankruptcy Battle",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2025/03/29/ftx-to-begin-usd11-4b-creditor-payouts-in-may-after-years-long-bankruptcy-battle",
        "published": "Sat, 29 Mar 2025 15:01:17 +0000",
        "summary": "FTX looks poised to recover a surprisingly high amount for creditors, a year after Sam Bankman-Fried was undone by a CoinDesk scoop (Adobe Firefly)",
        "content": "FTX, the collapsed cryptocurrency exchange once helmed by Sam Bankman-Fried, plans to begin paying its main creditors at the end of May, Bloomberg reported based on court proceedings in Delaware this week. The company has gathered $11.4 billion in cash to distribute to thousands of parties affected by its 2022 bankruptcy, with the first payments to major creditors set for May 30. These include institutional investors and firms that held crypto on FTX’s platform. Smaller creditors with claims below the $50,000 mark have already begun receiving distributions. FTX’s collapse left a financial crater and a trail of frustrated creditors—many of whom expected to be repaid in crypto, not dollars. Since the bankruptcy, the price of bitcoin has more than quadrupled, intensifying frustrations among those waiting for their assets back. The task of unwinding FTX’s balance sheet has been slowed by a large number of claims, many of them reportedly questionable. Andrew Dietderich, a bankruptcy attorney for the firm, told the court that FTX has received “27 quintillion” claims, Blloomberg reported, many of which are duplicates or outright fraudulent. Interest payments are compounding the urgency. While FTX earns only a modest return on its cash, legitimate creditors are entitled to 9% interest annually on unpaid claims. The longer it takes to pay, the more the company could owe. Read more: Nearly All FTX Creditors Will Get 118% of Their Funds Back in Cash, Estate Says in New Plan Francisco is a reporter for CoinDesk with a passion for cryptocurrencies and personal finance. Before joining CoinDesk he worked at major financial and crypto publications. He owns bitcoin, ether, solana, and PAXG above CoinDesk's $1,000 disclosure threshold. About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "FTX",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Sam Bankman-Fried",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "the end of May",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Bloomberg",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Delaware",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "this week",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "$11.4 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "thousands",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "2022",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "first",
                    "ORDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "May 30",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "50,000",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Andrew Dietderich",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "27",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "Blloomberg",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "9%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "annually",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "118%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "Their Funds Back",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "New Plan Francisco",
                    "EVENT"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "solana",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "1,000",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.069,
                    "neu": 0.873,
                    "pos": 0.058,
                    "compound": -0.5106
                },
                "label": "negative"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9971792697906494
                },
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.9999858140945435
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.999667763710022
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999806880950928
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "neutral",
            "entity_sentiment": {},
            "crypto_scores": {},
            "topics": [
                [
                    "payments",
                    "reported",
                    "financial",
                    "coindesk",
                    "bankruptcy",
                    "cash",
                    "crypto",
                    "claims",
                    "creditors",
                    "ftx"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "ftx",
                "creditors",
                "claims"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-03-29T21:07:57.528560+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "Why Is the Crypto Market Down Today? Bitcoin Drops to $82K as Traders Flee Risk Assets Amid Macro Worries",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2025/03/29/why-is-the-crypto-market-down-today-bitcoin-drops-to-usd82k-as-traders-flee-risk-assets-amid-macro-worries",
        "published": "Sat, 29 Mar 2025 13:51:25 +0000",
        "summary": "Stock market price charts (Anne Nygård/Unsplash)",
        "content": "Cryptocurrency prices have experienced a sharp decline over the last few hours, with bitcoin (BTC) now being down around 3% over the last 24 hours, while major altcoins including XRP, BNB, and SOL are down between 4% and 5% over the same period. The broader cryptocurrency market, represented by the CoinDesk 20 Index (CD20), lost around 3.3% of its value over the period. The sharp drop brings BTC’s performance down 1.7% for the week, while CD20 is down nearly 5%. Over the last 24 hours, over $300 million worth of long positions were liquidated on centralized cryptocurrency exchanges, while $38.8 million worth of shorts were liquidated on these platforms, according to CoinGlass data. The drop appears to be part of a wider derisking move among traders, as investors are anticipating the impact of President Donald Trump’s reciprocal tariffs that are set to come into effect on April 2. The move heightened after core Personal Consumption Expenditures (PCE) data came in hotter than expected on Friday. Just this week, consumer confidence data dipped further than expected, while the index for future expectations came in at a 12-year low, and well below levels associated with an incoming recession. This confluence of factors has seen investors reduce their exposure to risk assets and triggered a flight to safety. CoinDesk Data’s latest stablecoin report shows that gold-backed cryptocurrencies have benefitted from the risk-off move, as their market capitalization climbed above $1.4 billion in March. Gold-backed cryptocurrencies are, in fact, countering the market’s bearish trend. While the CD20 is down over 3% in the last 24-hour period, tokens including PAXG and XAUT are up 0.7% to over $3,100. These tokens are up more than 18% year-to-date, while BTC is down 12.5% and the CD20 index 28% so far this year. Francisco is a reporter for CoinDesk with a passion for cryptocurrencies and personal finance. Before joining CoinDesk he worked at major financial and crypto publications. He owns bitcoin, ether, solana, and PAXG above CoinDesk's $1,000 disclosure threshold. About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "the last few hours",
                    "TIME"
                ],
                [
                    "BTC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "around 3%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "the last 24 hours",
                    "TIME"
                ],
                [
                    "XRP",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "BNB",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "SOL",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "between 4% and 5%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "the same period",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "the CoinDesk 20 Index",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "around 3.3%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "1.7%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "the week",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "nearly 5%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "$300 million",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "$38.8 million",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinGlass",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Donald Trump",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "April 2",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Personal Consumption Expenditures",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "PCE",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Friday",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Just this week",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "12-year",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "$1.4 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "March",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "over 3%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "the last",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "24-hour",
                    "TIME"
                ],
                [
                    "PAXG",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "XAUT",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "0.7%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "over $3,100",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "more than 18%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "12.5%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "28%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "this year",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Francisco",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "solana",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "1,000",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.039,
                    "neu": 0.899,
                    "pos": 0.063,
                    "compound": 0.8074
                },
                "label": "positive"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.9999778270721436
                },
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.999618411064148
                },
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.9906778335571289
                },
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.4179556369781494
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.999996542930603
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "negative",
            "entity_sentiment": {},
            "crypto_scores": {},
            "topics": [
                [
                    "market",
                    "24",
                    "cryptocurrencies",
                    "btc",
                    "cryptocurrency",
                    "year",
                    "period",
                    "cd20",
                    "data",
                    "coindesk"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "coindesk",
                "data",
                "cd20"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-03-29T21:07:58.374633+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "Where All the SEC Cases Are",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2025/03/29/where-all-the-sec-cases-are",
        "published": "Sat, 29 Mar 2025 13:30:00 +0000",
        "summary": "The status of every SEC crypto case, minus Haliey Welch's. (Jesse Hamilton/CoinDesk)",
        "content": "The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission has dropped or paused over a dozen ongoing cases (and lost one) since U.S. President Donald Trump retook office just over two months ago and appointed Commissioner Mark Uyeda as acting chair. You’re reading State of Crypto, a CoinDesk newsletter looking at the intersection of cryptocurrency and government. Click here to sign up for future editions. The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission appears to have closed almost all of its outstanding crypto-related cases — at least the publicly disclosed ones — in the last two months since Mark Uyeda took over as acting chair of the agency. In many of the court filings, the SEC argued that it needs to pull these cases while the regulator's new crypto task force reassesses how exactly it applies securities laws to digital assets, though in at least some of these cases the SEC is leaving itself no recourse to sue again should it find some cryptos from previously active suits are indeed securities. TKTK Thursday If you’ve got thoughts or questions on what I should discuss next week or any other feedback you’d like to share, feel free to email me at nik@coindesk.com or find me on Bluesky @nikhileshde.bsky.social. You can also join the group conversation on Telegram. See ya’ll next week! Nikhilesh De is CoinDesk's managing editor for global policy and regulation, covering regulators, lawmakers and institutions. When he's not reporting on digital assets and policy, he can be found admiring Amtrak or building LEGO trains. He owns < $50 in BTC and < $20 in ETH. He was named the Association of Cryptocurrency Journalists and Researchers' Journalist of the Year in 2020. About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "over a dozen",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "one",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "U.S.",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Donald Trump",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "just over two months ago",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Mark Uyeda",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "the last two months",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "SEC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Thursday",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "next week",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "nik@coindesk.com",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Bluesky",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Telegram",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Amtrak",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "LEGO",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "50",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "BTC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "20",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "ETH",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "the Association of Cryptocurrency Journalists",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "2020",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.024,
                    "neu": 0.868,
                    "pos": 0.108,
                    "compound": 0.9682
                },
                "label": "positive"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9995953440666199
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9892873764038086
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9998680353164673
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999880790710449
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "neutral",
            "entity_sentiment": {},
            "crypto_scores": {},
            "topics": [
                [
                    "uyeda",
                    "mark",
                    "cryptocurrency",
                    "policy",
                    "months",
                    "sec",
                    "coindesk",
                    "crypto",
                    "cases",
                    "securities"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "securities",
                "cases",
                "crypto"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-03-29T21:07:59.124286+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "Bitcoin Plunges Below $84K after $115B Sell-Off Wipes Out Weekly Gains",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2025/03/28/bitcoin-plunges-below-usd84k-after-usd115b-sell-off-wipes-out-weekly-gains",
        "published": "Fri, 28 Mar 2025 21:08:30 +0000",
        "summary": "Bear (mana5280/Unsplash)",
        "content": "Hopes for the crypto recovery to continue vanished on Friday, as a market-wide rout erased virtually all gains from earlier this week. Bitcoin (BTC), hovering just below $88,000 a day ago, tumbled to $83,800 recently and is down 3.8% over the past 24 hours. The broad-market benchmark CoinDesk 20 Index declined 5.7%, with native cryptos Avalanche (AVAX), Polygon (POL), Near (NEAR), and Uniswap (UNI) all nursing almost 10% losses during the same period. Today's sell-off wiped out $115 billion of the total market value of cryptocurrencies, TradingView data shows. Ethereum's ether (ETH) declined over 6% to extend its downtrend against BTC, falling to its weakest relative price to the largest cryptocurrency since May 2020. Underscoring the bearish trend, spot ETH exchange-traded funds failed to attract any net inflows since early March, while their BTC counterparts saw over $1 billion of inflows in the past two weeks, according to Farside Investors data. The ugly crypto price action coincided with U.S. stocks selling off during the day on poor economic data, with the S&P 500 and the tech-heavy Nasdaq index down 2% and 2.8%, respectively. Crypto-focused stocks also suffered heavy losses: Strategy (MSTR), the largest corporate BTC holder, closed the day 10% lower, while crypto exchange Coinbase (COIN) dropped 7.7%. The February PCE inflation report, released this morning, showed a 2.5% year-over-year increase in the price index, with core inflation at 2.8%, slightly above expectations. Consumer spending showed a modest 0.4% rise, though inflation-adjusted figures indicate minimal growth, suggesting potential headwinds for economic growth. The Federal Reserve of Atlanta's GDPNow model now projects the U.S. economy to contract 2.8% in the first quarter, 0.5% adjusted for gold imports and exports, spurring stagflationary fears. The implementation of broad-scale U.S. tariffs next week—the so-called \"Liberation Day' on April 2, as the Trump administration refers to—also compounded investor concerns across markets. Bitcoin has closely correlated with the Nasdaq lately, so U.S. equities rolling over for another leg down could weigh on the broader crypto market. However, on a more optimistic note, today's decline could be BTC filling the price gap at around $84,000-$85,000 between Monday's open and the previous week's close on the Chicago Mercantile Exchange futures market. Historically, BTC usually revisited similar CME gaps and a drop to $84,000 was in the cards, CoinDesk senior analyst James Van Straten noted earlier this week. Read more: Bitcoin's Weekend Surge Forms Another CME Gap, Signaling Possible Drop Back \"At this stage it’s difficult to determine if we have already seen a bottom in 2025,\" Joel Kruger, market strategist at LMAX Group, said in a market note. Despite the on-going correction, he noted several positive trends such as crypto-friendly policies in the U.S. and more traditional financial firms entering the industry or expanding crypto offerings, which could bode well for digital assets later in the year. \"Any additional setbacks that we might see should be exceptionally well supported into the $70-75k area,\" he added. Krisztian Sandor is a U.S. markets reporter focusing on stablecoins, tokenization, real-world assets. He graduated from New York University's business and economic reporting program before joining CoinDesk. He holds BTC, SOL and ETH.\n About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "Friday",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "earlier this week",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "BTC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "just below $88,000",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "a day ago",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "83,800",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "3.8%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "the past 24 hours",
                    "TIME"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk 20 Index",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "5.7%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "Avalanche",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Polygon",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "POL",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "NEAR",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Uniswap",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "almost 10%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "Today",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "$115 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "TradingView",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Ethereum",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "ETH",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "6%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "May 2020",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "early March",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "$1 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "the past two weeks",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Farside Investors",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "U.S.",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "the day",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Nasdaq",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "2%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "2.8%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "MSTR",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "day",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "10%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "Coinbase",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "COIN",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "7.7%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "February",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "this morning",
                    "TIME"
                ],
                [
                    "2.5%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "0.4%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "The Federal Reserve of",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Atlanta",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "the first quarter",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "0.5%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "next week",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Liberation Day'",
                    "WORK_OF_ART"
                ],
                [
                    "April 2",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Trump",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "today",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "around $84,000-$85,000",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Monday",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "the previous week's",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "the Chicago Mercantile Exchange",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "CME",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "84,000",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "James Van Straten",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Bitcoin",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "2025",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Joel Kruger",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "LMAX Group",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "later in the year",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "70",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Krisztian Sandor",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "New York University's",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "SOL",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.062,
                    "neu": 0.87,
                    "pos": 0.068,
                    "compound": 0.1847
                },
                "label": "positive"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.9999873638153076
                },
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.9999651908874512
                },
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.9999265670776367
                },
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.9982719421386719
                },
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.9999966621398926
                },
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.9625996947288513
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9176117777824402
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "negative",
            "entity_sentiment": {
                "Avalanche": {
                    "sentiment": "negative",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 1
                },
                "Polygon": {
                    "sentiment": "negative",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 1
                },
                "Uniswap": {
                    "sentiment": "negative",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 1
                },
                "Ethereum": {
                    "sentiment": "negative",
                    "confidence": 0.9999,
                    "mentions": 1
                },
                "Trump": {
                    "sentiment": "negative",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 1
                },
                "Bitcoin": {
                    "sentiment": "negative",
                    "confidence": 0.9999,
                    "mentions": 3
                },
                "2025": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 0.8569,
                    "mentions": 1
                }
            },
            "crypto_scores": {
                "2025": 0.2714,
                "Bitcoin": -0.6999,
                "Ethereum": -0.8999,
                "Avalanche": -0.9,
                "Polygon": -0.9,
                "Uniswap": -0.9,
                "Trump": -0.9
            },
            "topics": [
                [
                    "coindesk",
                    "economic",
                    "bitcoin",
                    "price",
                    "week",
                    "day",
                    "000",
                    "market",
                    "crypto",
                    "btc"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "btc",
                "crypto",
                "market"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-03-29T21:08:01.589761+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "President Trump Pardons Arthur Hayes, BitMEX and 3 Other Co-Founders and Employee",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2025/03/28/president-trump-pardons-arthur-hayes-2-other-bitmex-co-founders-cnbc",
        "published": "Fri, 28 Mar 2025 20:04:27 +0000",
        "summary": "Arthur Hayes speaks on stage during Bitcoin Conference 2023 (Photo by Jason Koerner/Getty Images for Bitcoin Magazine)",
        "content": "Arthur Hayes, the former CEO of crypto exchange BitMEX, has been granted a pardon by U.S. President Donald Trump, a White House official confirmed Friday.  Trump also pardoned Hayes’ co-founders at BitMEX, Samuel Reed and Benjamin Delo, as well as senior employee Greg Dwyer and BitMEX's operating entity, HDR Global Trading, a BitMEX spokesperson said. CNBC first reported the pardons, which the White House said were signed on Thursday. In 2020, the U.S. Department of Justice (DOJ) brought charges against BitMEX, its three co-founders, and its first employee, Dwyer, accusing them of violating the Bank Secrecy Act (BSA). Prosecutors alleged BitMEX advertised itself as a place where customers could use its platform virtually anonymously, without providing basic know-your-customer (KYC) information. All four individuals eventually pleaded guilty and were sentenced to fines and probationary sentences. The exchange itself pleaded guilty to violating the BSA last year. Hayes faced two years of probation; Delo spent 30 months on probation and Reed 18 months on probation. Dwyer got 12 months of probation. In a statement, Delo said he and his colleagues had been \"wrongfully targeted.\"  \"This full and unconditional pardon by President Trump is a vindication of the position we have always held — that BitMEX, my co-founders and I should never have been charged with a criminal offense through an obscure, antiquated law,\" he said. \"As the most successful crypto exchange of its kind, we were wrongfully made to serve as an example, sacrificed for political reasons and used to send inconsistent regulatory signals. I’m sincerely grateful to the President for granting this pardon to me and my co-founders.\" Hayes just said \"thank you\" on X (formerly known as Twitter). Thank you @POTUS The Commodity Futures Trading Commission ordered BitMEX to pay $100 million for violating the Commodity Exchange Act and other CFTC regulations in 2021, separately from its DOJ settlements. Attorneys representing Hayes, Delo and Reed did not immediately return requests for comment. The reported pardons come just a day after Trump granted a pardon to Trevor Milton, the former CEO of Nikola Motors who was previously convicted of fraud in 2022. In January, Trump made good on long-standing promises to pardon Silk Road creator Ross Ulbricht, who was 11 years into a draconian sentence of double life in prison plus 40 years, with no possibility of parole. Since Ulbricht’s pardon, former FTX CEO and convicted fraudster Sam Bankman-Fried has been angling for his own pardon, attempting to curry favor with the Trump administration and appearing on Tucker Carlson in an unauthorized jailhouse interview that landed him in solitary confinement. Former Binance CEO Changpeng \"CZ\" Zhao, who pleaded guilty to the same charge as Hayes and served four months in prison last year — making him not only the richest person to ever go to prison in the U.S., but also the only person to ever serve jail time for violating the BSA — has denied reports that he, too, is seeking a pardon from President Trump. But, Zhao admitted in a recent X post that “no felon would mind a pardon, especially being the only one in US history who was ever sentenced to prison for a single BSA charge.” UPDATE (March 28, 2025, 20:40 UTC): Adds Delo statement and White House official. UPDATE (March 28, 21:06 UTC): Adds Hayes. UPDATE (March 29, 04:15 UTC): Adds Dwyer and HDR. On the news team at CoinDesk, Cheyenne focuses on crypto regulation and crime. Cheyenne is originally from Houston, Texas. She studied political science at Tulane University in Louisiana. In December 2021, she graduated from CUNY's Craig Newmark Graduate School of Journalism, where she focused on business and economics reporting. She has no significant crypto holdings.  Nikhilesh De is CoinDesk's managing editor for global policy and regulation, covering regulators, lawmakers and institutions. When he's not reporting on digital assets and policy, he can be found admiring Amtrak or building LEGO trains. He owns < $50 in BTC and < $20 in ETH. He was named the Association of Cryptocurrency Journalists and Researchers' Journalist of the Year in 2020. About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "Arthur Hayes",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "BitMEX",
                    "EXCHANGE"
                ],
                [
                    "U.S.",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Donald Trump",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "White House",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Friday",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Trump",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Hayes",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Samuel Reed",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Benjamin Delo",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Greg Dwyer",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "CNBC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "first",
                    "ORDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "the White House",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Thursday",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "2020",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "the U.S. Department of Justice",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "three",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "Dwyer",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "BSA",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "KYC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "four",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "last year",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "two years",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Delo",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "30 months",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "18 months",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "12 months",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Twitter",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "The Commodity Futures Trading Commission",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "$100 million",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "the Commodity Exchange Act",
                    "LAW"
                ],
                [
                    "CFTC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "2021",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "DOJ",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Reed",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Trevor Milton",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Nikola Motors",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "2022",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "January",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Silk Road",
                    "FAC"
                ],
                [
                    "Ross Ulbricht",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "11 years",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "40 years",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Ulbricht",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "FTX",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Sam Bankman-Fried",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Tucker Carlson",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Binance",
                    "EXCHANGE"
                ],
                [
                    "Changpeng \"CZ\" Zhao",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "four months",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Zhao",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "US",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "March 28, 2025",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "UTC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "March 28",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "March 29",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "HDR",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Cheyenne",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Houston",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Texas",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Tulane University",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Louisiana",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "December 2021",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "CUNY",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Craig Newmark Graduate School of Journalism",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Nikhilesh De",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "Amtrak",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "LEGO",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "50",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "BTC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "20",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "ETH",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "the Association of Cryptocurrency Journalists",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.08,
                    "neu": 0.83,
                    "pos": 0.09,
                    "compound": -0.467
                },
                "label": "negative"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9258579015731812
                },
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.9995447993278503
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9968536496162415
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.8420323729515076
                },
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.9102312922477722
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.5679092407226562
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999192953109741
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999843835830688
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999922513961792
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "neutral",
            "entity_sentiment": {
                "Trump": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 0.9663,
                    "mentions": 7
                },
                "Tucker Carlson": {
                    "sentiment": "negative",
                    "confidence": 0.9824,
                    "mentions": 1
                },
                "Cheyenne": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 2
                }
            },
            "crypto_scores": {
                "Trump": 0.6933,
                "Cheyenne": 0.4,
                "Tucker Carlson": -0.8824
            },
            "topics": [
                [
                    "months",
                    "probation",
                    "president",
                    "prison",
                    "delo",
                    "said",
                    "hayes",
                    "trump",
                    "bitmex",
                    "pardon"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "pardon",
                "bitmex",
                "trump"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-03-29T21:08:03.296340+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "FDIC Reverses U.S. Crypto Banking Policy That Demanded Prior Approvals",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2025/03/28/fdic-reverses-u-s-crypto-banking-policy-that-demanded-prior-approvals",
        "published": "Fri, 28 Mar 2025 18:33:38 +0000",
        "summary": "Federal Deposit Insurance Corp. (Jesse Hamilton/CoinDesk)",
        "content": "The Federal Deposit Insurance Corp. will no longer instruct banks to get prior sign-off before they engage in crypto activities — a standard that was set in 2022 and that effectively severed institutions from the digital assets sector as they waited for approvals that never came. The FDIC, which is the chief federal supervisor of thousands of typically smaller banks and runs the banking industry's government backstop, had occupied a significant role in the crypto debanking saga. A courtroom fight with crypto exchange Coinbase had recently unveiled dozens of letters between the regulator and banks it supervised. In that 2022 correspondence, the FDIC had instructed them to steer clear of new crypto matters while it hashed out policies, though the agency never developed any and left bankers hanging. The new industry guidance issued on Friday comes after President Donald Trump elevated a crypto-friendly leadership at the FDIC and other financial regulators and has directed his administration to open doors for the industry. “With today’s action, the FDIC is turning the page on the flawed approach of the past three years,” said FDIC Acting Chairman Travis Hill, in a statement. “I expect this to be one of several steps the FDIC will take to lay out a new approach for how banks can engage in crypto- and blockchain-related activities in accordance with safety and soundness standards.” Read More: Trump's FDIC Chief Rethinks Crypto Guidance as U.S. Senators Probe Debanking Banks that were once expected to get pre-approvals on crypto matters can now forge ahead, as long as they're appropriately considering the risks. Bo Hines, the White House's director of its council of digital assets advisers cheered the FDIC's move in a social media post, calling it a \"huge step forward.\" The guidance to seek pre-approvals was a common stance across all three U.S. banking agencies, including the Federal Reserve and the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency. The OCC also acted recently to rescind its similar 2022 guidance, which had emerged as the digital assets sector was beset by failure and high-profile fraud, and global exchange FTX was steering toward disaster. Read More: OCC Says Banks Can Engage in Crypto Custody and Certain Stablecoin Activities UPDATE (March 28, 2025, 18:42 UTC): Adds comment from a White House official. Jesse Hamilton is CoinDesk's deputy managing editor on the Global Policy and Regulation team, based in Washington, D.C. Before joining CoinDesk in 2022, he worked for more than a decade covering Wall Street regulation at Bloomberg News and Businessweek, writing about the early whisperings among federal agencies trying to decide what to do about crypto. He’s won several national honors in his reporting career, including from his time as a war correspondent in Iraq and as a police reporter for newspapers. Jesse is a graduate of Western Washington University, where he studied journalism and history. He has no crypto holdings.  About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "The Federal Deposit Insurance Corp.",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "2022",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "FDIC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "thousands",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "Coinbase",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "dozens",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "Friday",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Donald Trump",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "the past three years",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Travis Hill",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Trump",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "U.S.",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Probe Debanking Banks",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Hines",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "the White House's",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "three",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "the Federal Reserve",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "OCC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Banks Can Engage",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "March 28, 2025",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "18:42",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "UTC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "White House",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Jesse Hamilton",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "the Global Policy and Regulation",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Washington",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "D.C.",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "more than a decade",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Bloomberg News",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Businessweek",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Iraq",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Jesse",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Western Washington University",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.053,
                    "neu": 0.869,
                    "pos": 0.078,
                    "compound": 0.765
                },
                "label": "positive"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9904206991195679
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9997513890266418
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9903194904327393
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.8824748396873474
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9974550604820251
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999703168869019
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9979614019393921
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "neutral",
            "entity_sentiment": {
                "Trump": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 0.9993,
                    "mentions": 2
                }
            },
            "crypto_scores": {
                "Trump": 0.3999
            },
            "topics": [
                [
                    "activities",
                    "approvals",
                    "new",
                    "engage",
                    "2022",
                    "federal",
                    "guidance",
                    "banks",
                    "fdic",
                    "crypto"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "crypto",
                "fdic",
                "banks"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-03-29T21:08:04.299893+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "CoreWeave Stock Debuts at $39 After Selling Shares for $40 A Piece",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2025/03/28/coreweave-stock-debuts-at-usd39-after-selling-shares-for-usd40-a-piece",
        "published": "Fri, 28 Mar 2025 18:02:54 +0000",
        "summary": "Cloud Based Artificial Intelligence Computing Company CoreWeave Has IPO On Nasdaq Exchange. (Michael M. Santiago/Getty Images)",
        "content": "Shares of CoreWeave (CRWV) opened at $39 apiece during the company’s debut on Nasdaq on Friday afternoon, just under its initial public offering which closed Thursday evening. The cloud computing firm had sold roughly 37.5 million shares at $40 each, raising about $1.5 billion for its initial public offering (IPO), making it the largest tech offering since 2021. It had, however, initially planned to file the offering at $47 to $55 a share at a much higher valuation than it ultimately saw. Nvidia, an early investor in the company, placed a $250 million order in the offering. Some experts speculated that the stock’s debut wouldn’t see the success it had hoped for. Bloomberg Opinion US technology columnist Dave Lee, for example, pointed out the company’s large debt, reliance on just a few big customers and lack of diversity in revenue may be an issue. “CoreWeave stands to be a bellwether for the AI industry as a whole — a must-watch stock as questions about return on investment grow ever louder,” Lee wrote in an op-ed on Friday. “Even the slightest indication of shakiness in the belief of AI sends investors into a tailspin.” The current risk-off environment caused by the overall macro situation in the U.S., mainly due to recent tariffs imposed by U.S. President Donald Trump, which has caused a sell off in tech stocks, could also have weighed on CoreWeave’s IPO. Helene is a New York-based news reporter at CoinDesk, covering news about Wall Street, the rise of the spot bitcoin exchange-traded funds (ETFs) and updates on crypto exchanges. She is also the co-host of CoinDesk's Markets Daily show on Spotify and Youtube. Helene is a recent graduate of New York University's business and economic reporting program and has appeared on CBS News, YahooFinance and Nasdaq TradeTalks. She holds BTC and ETH. About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "39",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Nasdaq",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Friday",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "afternoon",
                    "TIME"
                ],
                [
                    "Thursday",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "evening",
                    "TIME"
                ],
                [
                    "roughly 37.5 million",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "40",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "about $1.5 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "IPO",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "2021",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "47",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "55",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Nvidia",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "$250 million",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Bloomberg Opinion US",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Dave Lee",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "CoreWeave",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "AI",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Lee",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "U.S.",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Donald Trump",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "CoreWeave’s IPO",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "New York",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk's Markets Daily",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Spotify",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Youtube",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "New York University's",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "CBS News",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "YahooFinance",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Nasdaq TradeTalks",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "BTC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "ETH",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.026,
                    "neu": 0.932,
                    "pos": 0.042,
                    "compound": 0.7269
                },
                "label": "positive"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.963140606880188
                },
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.9999783039093018
                },
                {
                    "label": "negative",
                    "score": 0.9960696697235107
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9999934434890747
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "neutral",
            "entity_sentiment": {
                "47": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 0.8624,
                    "mentions": 1
                },
                "Lee": {
                    "sentiment": "negative",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 2
                }
            },
            "crypto_scores": {
                "47": 0.2725,
                "Lee": -0.8
            },
            "topics": [
                [
                    "initial",
                    "million",
                    "ipo",
                    "helene",
                    "recent",
                    "public",
                    "coreweave",
                    "news",
                    "company",
                    "offering"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "offering",
                "company",
                "news"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-03-29T21:08:05.072704+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "Crypto Card Firm Baanx Partners With Circle for Rewards Wallet",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/business/2025/03/28/crypto-card-firm-baanx-partners-with-circle-for-rewards-wallet",
        "published": "Fri, 28 Mar 2025 18:00:00 +0000",
        "summary": "16:9 crop The Baanx team (Baanx) (2024)",
        "content": "Baanx, a cryptocurrency debit card enabler for the likes of MetaMask and 1inch, has introduced a rewards wallet combining on-chain finance with traditional loyalty perks and discounts, using underlying technology from Circle, the provider of the USDC stablecoin. Built on Circle’s programmable wallet tech, the Baanx platform allows crypto holders access to cashback, fee discounts, subscription perks and exclusive gated experiences, according to a press release. An ongoing convergence between traditional card networks and the on-chain world of stablecoins and decentralized finance (DeFi) has seen Mastercard partner with Web3 wallet MetaMask, and more recently reports of Visa in talks with Sam Altman’s World Network. The rewards wallet offering helps bridge the gap between blockchain and everyday financial needs, said Baanx Chief Commercial Officer Simon Jones. “We've built the Rewards Wallet using Circle to offer rewards on a crypto debit card that are unprecedented, and so incentivizing users to go down the route of non-custodial spend,” Jones said in an interview. “For instance, if you look at the MataMask card, it’s up to 6% cash-back for the first month.” Circle, famous as the creator of the $60 billion stablecoin USDC, offers programmable wallet infrastructure that allows for adding features to multiple crypto projects without having to change the user interface, Jones said. “We are pushing USDC as the main treasury token and incentive program within these products, as opposed to Tether [USDT],” he said. Sanja Kon, VP of partnerships & business development, Europe at Circle said in a statement: “Circle Wallets provide a fantastic foundation for the Rewards Wallet. By integrating this technology, Baanx is bringing real-world value to crypto users in new and exciting ways.”  Ian Allison is a senior reporter at CoinDesk, focused on institutional and enterprise adoption of cryptocurrency and blockchain technology. Prior to that, he covered fintech for the International Business Times in London and Newsweek online. He won the State Street Data and Innovation journalist of the year award in 2017, and was runner up the following year. He also earned CoinDesk an honourable mention in the 2020 SABEW Best in Business awards. His November 2022 FTX scoop, which brought down the exchange and its boss Sam Bankman-Fried, won a Polk award, Loeb award and New York Press Club award. Ian graduated from the University of Edinburgh. He holds ETH. About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "MetaMask",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "1inch",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "Circle",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "USDC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Baanx",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "DeFi",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Mastercard",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Visa",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Sam Altman’s",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Baanx Chief",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Simon Jones",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Jones",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "MataMask",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "up to 6%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "the first month",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "$60 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "Sanja Kon",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "VP",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "partnerships & business development",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Europe",
                    "LOC"
                ],
                [
                    "Circle Wallets",
                    "WORK_OF_ART"
                ],
                [
                    "the Rewards Wallet",
                    "WORK_OF_ART"
                ],
                [
                    "Ian Allison",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "the International Business Times",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "London",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Newsweek",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "the State Street Data",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "the year",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "2017",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "the following year",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "2020",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "November 2022",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "FTX scoop",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "Sam Bankman-Fried",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "New York Press Club",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Ian",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "the University of Edinburgh",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "ETH",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
            "vader_sentiment": {
                "scores": {
                    "neg": 0.0,
                    "neu": 0.818,
                    "pos": 0.182,
                    "compound": 0.9972
                },
                "label": "positive"
            },
            "bert_sentiment": [
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.6587861776351929
                },
                {
                    "label": "positive",
                    "score": 0.8956351280212402
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9670382142066956
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.8001274466514587
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.9998409748077393
                },
                {
                    "label": "neutral",
                    "score": 0.991969883441925
                }
            ],
            "bert_sentiment_summary": "neutral",
            "entity_sentiment": {
                "Circle": {
                    "sentiment": "positive",
                    "confidence": 0.9093,
                    "mentions": 5
                },
                "Baanx": {
                    "sentiment": "positive",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 4
                },
                "Visa": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 0.9974,
                    "mentions": 1
                },
                "Jones": {
                    "sentiment": "positive",
                    "confidence": 0.995,
                    "mentions": 3
                },
                "London": {
                    "sentiment": "neutral",
                    "confidence": 1.0,
                    "mentions": 1
                }
            },
            "crypto_scores": {
                "Circle": 1.4093,
                "Baanx": 1.4,
                "Jones": 1.295,
                "London": 0.3,
                "Visa": 0.2995
            },
            "topics": [
                [
                    "usdc",
                    "technology",
                    "baanx",
                    "card",
                    "crypto",
                    "award",
                    "said",
                    "rewards",
                    "circle",
                    "wallet"
                ]
            ],
            "top_keywords_tfidf": [
                "wallet",
                "circle",
                "rewards"
            ]
        },
        "timestamp": "2025-03-29T21:08:06.258659+00:00"
    },
    {
        "title": "CoinDesk Weekly Recap: Stablecoins, Stablecoins, Stablecoins",
        "link": "https://www.coindesk.com/coindesk-news/2025/03/28/coindesk-weekly-recap-stablecoins-stablecoins-stablecoins",
        "published": "Fri, 28 Mar 2025 16:46:08 +0000",
        "summary": "Don Jnr",
        "content": "It was a bad week for crypto prices, with BTC and ETH both falling and the CoinDesk 20, which covers 80% of the market, losing 7% since Monday.  But less speculative assets showed plenty of volume. Stablecoins, in particular, were the name of the game this week.  The U.S. House introduced a stablecoin bill, following up on the Senate version that was approved by committee last week. Jesse Hamilton reported. Wyoming (aka “The Blockchain State”) wants its own stablecoin and it’s testing the idea on Avalanche, Solana and Ethereum, Kris Sandor reported. World Liberty Financial (WLFI), the financial protocol backed by Donald Trump and his family, confirmed the launch of its stablecoin (USD1) this week. And Don Trump Jr. trumpeted the news at the DC Blockchain Summit. Meanwhile, Fidelity Investment, an early TradFi innovator in crypto, is in the advanced stages of launching its own stablecoin. The venture is part of a strategy to enter the tokenized bond market, Jamie Crawley reported. Meanwhile, Circle, the issuer of the second biggest stablecoin (USDC), has finally secured a license to operate in Japan in partnership with local heavyweight SBI Holdings, Sam Reynolds reported. In news from our Europe team, Ian Allison had a scoop about Sam Altman's World Network holding talks with Visa on linking on-chain card features to a self-custody crypto wallet. Will Canny heard from a source that Sam Hill, Zodia Custody's COO had left and was returning to a role in TradFi. He was able to persuade the Standard Chartered-backed company to confirm the move and we beat the competition with the story. Canny followed up the next day with a story, unreported elsewhere, on the wave of senior staff losses at crypto prime broker FalconX. (BlackRock, by contrast, was adding talent to its digital assets team in the U.S.) We continued to report on Strategy (MicroStrategy), pioneer of the corporate bitcoin treasury. Christine Lee had a two-hour interview with executive chairman Michael Saylor, where he mused about bitcoin as a $200 trillion asset and promised to burn bitcoin in the name of immortality.  Strategy has invested about $33 billion in bitcoin so far through various stock offerings, both common and preferred. And James Van Straten explained the differences between the company's fund-raising instruments for bitcoin purchases. Tom Carreras followed up later with a nice piece showing how MSTR stockholders might be at risk from Saylor’s buy-every-bitcoin strategy. Meanwhile, the SEC continued to drop enforcement actions against crypto companies (Immutable was the latest, as Cheyenne Ligon reported). But, strangely, one involving Unicoin stayed open, much to the CEO’s chagrin. It almost felt like a normal sort of week — more incremental than monumental. But then the president’s own media company announced that it was launching its own ETFs and ETPs with Crypto.com. Thankfully, crypto still has the power to surprise. Benjamin Schiller is CoinDesk's managing editor for features and opinion. Previously, he was editor-in-chief at BREAKER Magazine and a staff writer at Fast Company. He holds some ETH, BTC and LINK.  Sheldon Reback is CoinDesk editorial's Regional Head of Europe. Before joining the company, he spent 26 years as an editor at Bloomberg News, where he worked on beats as diverse as stock markets and the retail industry as well as covering the dot-com bubble of 2000-2002. He managed the Bloomberg Terminal's main news page and also worked on a global project to produce short, chart-based stories across the newsroom. He previously worked as a journalist for a number of technology magazines in Hong Kong. Sheldon has a degree in industrial chemistry and an MBA. He owns ether and bitcoin below CoinDesk's notifiable limit. About Contact",
        "analysis": {
            "entities": [
                [
                    "a bad week",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "BTC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "ETH",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "the CoinDesk 20",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "80%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "7%",
                    "PERCENT"
                ],
                [
                    "Monday",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "this week",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "The U.S. House",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Senate",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "last week",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Jesse Hamilton",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "The Blockchain State",
                    "WORK_OF_ART"
                ],
                [
                    "Avalanche",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Solana",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Ethereum",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Kris Sandor",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "World Liberty Financial (WLFI",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Donald Trump",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "USD1",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Don Trump Jr.",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "the DC Blockchain Summit",
                    "FAC"
                ],
                [
                    "Fidelity Investment",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Jamie Crawley",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Circle",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "second",
                    "ORDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "USDC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Japan",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "SBI Holdings",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Sam Reynolds",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Europe",
                    "LOC"
                ],
                [
                    "Ian Allison",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Sam Altman's",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "World Network",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Visa",
                    "CRYPTO"
                ],
                [
                    "Will Canny",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Sam Hill",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Zodia Custody's",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Standard Chartered",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Canny",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "the next day",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "BlackRock",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "U.S.",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "MicroStrategy",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Christine Lee",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "two-hour",
                    "TIME"
                ],
                [
                    "Michael Saylor",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "$200 trillion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "about $33 billion",
                    "MONEY"
                ],
                [
                    "James Van Straten",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Tom Carreras",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "MSTR",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Saylor’s",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "SEC",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Cheyenne Ligon",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "one",
                    "CARDINAL"
                ],
                [
                    "Unicoin",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Crypto.com",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Benjamin Schiller",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "CoinDesk",
                    "PRODUCT"
                ],
                [
                    "BREAKER Magazine",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Fast Company",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Sheldon Reback",
                    "PERSON"
                ],
                [
                    "Regional Head of",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "26 years",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "Bloomberg News",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "2000-2002",
                    "DATE"
                ],
                [
                    "the Bloomberg Terminal's",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "Hong Kong",
                    "GPE"
                ],
                [
                    "Sheldon",
                    "ORG"
                ],
                [
                    "MBA",
                    "WORK_OF_ART"
                ],
                [
                    "Contact",
                    "GPE"
                ]
            ],
